Kasun Abaywardana

Software Engineer

Phone: +6581503134

Email: abaywardanakasun@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kasun-lakmal-abaywardana/

Nationality: Srilankan

Gender: Male

Date of Birth: 05-07-1991



Detail-oriented professional with 7 years of work experience in the IT industry. Possessing in-depth knowledge of modern web design and development, specializing in frontend development using ReactJS and Angular 2+. Also experienced in backend development using Node.js with MongoDB, Firebase, and AWS Lambda, as well as hybrid mobile app development using frameworks such as Ionic, Cordova, and React Native. Demonstrated dedication, self-learning ability, and motivation, capable of working independently and as an efficient team player with excellent leadership capabilities.

Technical Skills

- Frontend Frameworks: React JS, Angular 2+
- Backend Frameworks: Node JS, Nest JS, Express JS, Kony
- Programming Languages: Java Script, TypeScript, Java
- Styling: CSS, SCSS
- Serverless Technologies: AWS Lambda, API Gateway, Firebase cloud functions, AWS S3, AWS CloudFront
- Database management: MongoDB, Firebase real-time DB, PgSql
- Hybrid mobile development: Cordova, Ionic 3, React Native
- Version Control: Bitbucket, Github, Github
- CI/CD: Jenkins, Bamboo CI/CD
- **Testing:** Unit testing & e2e testing, Load testing (jest, react testing-library)
- Project management: JIRA, Confluence, Planning Poker
- IDE: VS Code, Android Studio

Professional Experience

Senior Software Engineer - Cognizant Technology Solutions, Singapore Nov 2022 - May 2023

Associate Tech Lead - BISTEC Global Services (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka Feb 2022- Nov 2022

Senior Software Engineer - Softcodeit Solutions (Pvt) Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka March 2021-Feb 2022

Senior Software Engineer - SDB Bank (UPay), Colombo, Sri Lanka Jan 2018 - Feb 2021

Software Engineer - Payment Services (Pvt) Ltd (Upay), Colombo, Sri Lanka Apr 2017 - Dec 2017

Software Engineer - Crowderia (Pvt) (Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka Jul 2016 - Apr 2017

Associate Software Engineer - Crowderia (Pvt) (Ltd, Colombo, Sri Lanka Aug 2015 - Jun 2016

Project Experience

XGOWHERE - Senior Software Engineer

Nov 2022 - May 2023

A comprehensive set of web applications aims to aid the general public in Singapore in discovering places and acquiring knowledge about the diverse services offered by these establishments. The application comprises both back-end and front-end components, back-end based on serverless architecture.

Major Technologies & Tools

React JS, Node JS, Nest JS, CSS, AWS Lambda, Jest, AWS SDK, AWS S3, Cloud Watch, API Gateway, Bitbucket, Bamboo CI/CD, AWS CloudFront (CDN), Jira, Confluence

Responsibilities

- Implement new features and bug fixes in React JS for frontend enhancements and improved user interface.
- Develop new APIs and perform bug fixes in Node.js to enhance backend functionality.
- Collaborate with the project managers and UI/UX designers to ensure that the new features meet business requirements.
- Implement unit testing and end-to-end testing to ensure that the application is stable and error-free.
- Participate in code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards.
- Perform minor configurations on the CI/CD pipeline depending on the situation.
- Participate in agile processes such as daily stand-up's, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings.
- Document technical specifications, design decisions, and relevant information for knowledge sharing and application maintainability.

TAFI - Associate Tech lead

Mar 2022- Nov 2022

A tax planning & lodgment application catered for individual income taxpayers, which automates the end-to-end process on the cloud. The application is comprised of three primary components: three web-based applications (Admin portal, Tax practice portal & client portal).

Major Technologies & Tools

React JS, Node JS Express, mongo DB, Redis, SCSS, NX Console, Azure DevOps, VS Code, Jira, Confluence

Responsibilities

- Develop the full project structure using React JS under the Tech Lead's supervision.
- Develop new features in front-end applications using React JS.
- Develop new API in back-end applications using Node JS Express.
- Participate in the software development lifecycle from requirements gathering to deployment.
- Work closely with the product owner and tech lead to define project goals, deliverables, and timelines.
- Actively collaborate with the Tech Lead to design the technical architecture of software systems.
- Perform peer code reviews to ensure high-quality code standards.
- Guide and mentor 3 junior team members.
- Participate in UI design reviews and contribute ideas to improve application quality.
- Participate in agile processes such as daily stand-up's, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings to ensure that the project is on track and meets business objectives.
- Participate in the development of technical specifications and design decisions to ensure knowledge sharing and maintainability of the application.

Legacy Web application that comprises a data visualization tool at its core and a low-code suite for enterprises to support road-mapping, risk planning, and strategic decision-making.

Major Technologies & Tools

Angular 9, JavaScript, .NET Core, SQL Server, Azure, git, Jira, Confluence

Responsibilities

- Collaborate with team members to identify and fix legacy issues in the web client application.
- Refactor un-scalable code in the client web application to improve performance and maintainability.
- Work closely with the project manager to identify the project domain, main functionalities, and technical requirements.
- Ensure that code adheres to best practices, coding standards, and company guidelines.
- Participate in agile processes such as daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings to ensure that the project is on track and meets business objectives.

AVATARIN - Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2020 - Sep 2021

The platform is a comprehensive web and mobile-based solution designed specifically for physically disabled individuals, facilitating seamless connections with robots located in public places. By leveraging the platform, users gain the ability to purchase dedicated time slots, enabling them to control and maneuver the robots effortlessly through an intuitive mobile or web application.

Major Technologies & Tools

React JS, Redux, MUI, Node JS, mongo db, JWT, SCSS, AWS EC2, AWS S3, Jira

Responsibilities

- Implement new user journeys and bug fixes in React JS with MUI for frontend enhancements and improved user interface.
- Develop new APIs using Node.js and MongoDB to provide robust support for both web and mobile applications.
- Collaborate closely with the Tech Lead to identify areas of improvement, optimize performance, and enhance the scalability of the project.
- Conduct R&D on real-time communication between the web server and physical devices.
- Conduct code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards.
- Participate in agile processes such as daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings to ensure that the project is on track and meets business objectives.

ONLINE BANKING SOLUTION - Senior Software Engineer

Mar 2021- Jan 2022

Online Banking solution for credit union (USA) customers to facilitate online banking and specific third-party services. The application is comprised of separate web and mobile components, both based on a customized JavaScript framework (Kony).

Major Technologies & Tools

Kony, JavaScript, Java, Fabric pre-processors, Bitbucket, Android studio

Responsibilities

- Develop and customize front-end functionality using JavaScript to improve user experience and interface.
- Develop pre-processors using Java for the backend to improve the functionality and scalability of the application.
- Optimize existing code by refactoring to improve maintainability and scalability.
- Collaborate with designers and project managers to ensure that the application meets business requirements and user needs.
- Conduct unit testing to ensure stable and error-free application. Participate in code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards.
- Troubleshoot and resolve issues reported by users or identified through testing.
- Participate in agile processes such as daily stand-up's, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings to ensure that the project is on track and meets business objectives.

UPay - Senior Software Engineer

Apr 2017- Feb 2021

UPay, Sri Lanka's award-winning payments app gives you an innovative experience when accessing all your retail payment needs. Instant reloads, Utility bill payments, Book a movie ticket or a doctor's appointment, Online banking facility, and many more- all with just a few taps on your mobile or web.

Major Technologies & Tools

Angular 6, SCSS, Cordova, Java 8, Spring boot, MySQL, Node JS, Firebase, Google Analytics, Google Cloud functions, Android Studio, X-code, Bitbucket, Jira, Confluence

Responsibilities

- Develop new features and modules using Angular and Cordova for hybrid mobile applications to enhance the functionality and user experience of the app.
- Develop partial back-end functionality using Node JS with Firebase to improve the performance and scalability of the application.
- Develop Native Android and IOS plugins to connect the wallet to the JUST PAY switch system.
- Collaborate with UI designers and product owners to ensure that the app meets business requirements and user needs and is visually appealing.
- Conduct peer code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards.
- Actively participate in agile practices such as daily stand-ups, sprint planning, and retrospective meetings.
- Contributed to tech talk sessions to promote knowledge sharing among the team.

Back-Office Admin Panel for Upay - Software Engineer

Feb 2018 - Mar 2019

The admin panel is all based on back-office operations of UPay payment wallet. The application's front-end is developed using React with MUI, while the back-end is built on Java (Spring Boot), Firebase, and MySQL. This is a support application for the previous banking Wallet.

Major Technologies & Tools

React JS, Redux, JS PDF, SCSS, Java 8, Spring boot, MySQL, Bitbucket

Responsibilities

- Develop back-office functionality in React JS to enhance the management of the support application for payment wallet.
- Implement report generation using React JS with JS PDF and Excel JS to provide valuable insights to the back office and management and improve their processes.

- Conduct peer code reviews to ensure code quality and adherence to coding standards.
- As a support application for the Upay payment wallet, this project closely collaborates with the main project (UPay) to ensure seamless integration and successful delivery of the overall product.

BP-SYSTEM - Software Engineer

Jun 2019 - Jan 2020

The simple web-based platform allows business owners to create their own business processes, and users can manage their processes on the platform. This project's web application front-end is built on React, while the back-end is developed using Java (Spring Boot) and MySQL.

Major Technologies & Tools

React JS, Redux, MUI, SCSS, Java 8, Spring boot, MySQL, Bitbucket

Responsibilities

- Develop new functionalities in the front-end using React, including designing and implementing UI components, managing state, and optimizing performance.
- Fix bugs in the front-end existing modules.
- Participate in peer code reviews to identify issues, provide feedback, and ensure that best practices are being followed.
- Conduct R&D on diagram drawing on HTML canvas to create custom visualizations that are performant and scalable.
- Configure and maintain CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins.
- Participate in agile processes such as daily stand-up's, sprint planning, sprint review, and retrospective meetings.

MOBILE POS - Software Engineer

Feb 2018 - Jul 2018

Mobile-based POS system for QR payments. In this project, the mobile application front-end is built on React Native, while the admin panel is developed using React. The back-end is built on Java (Spring Boot) and MySQL.

Major Technologies & Tools

React JS, React Native, Redux, SCSS, Java 8, Spring boot, MySQL, Bitbucket

Responsibilities

- Develop new mobile app functionalities using React Native to enhance the user experience and meet business objectives.
- Develop admin panel functionalities using React JS to support the management of the mobile app and ensure seamless operation.
- Participate in agile processes such as sprint planning, daily stand-ups, and retrospective meetings.

Grade5 (Examination Portal) - Associate Software Engineer

Aug 2015 - Mar 2017

An educational portal to Sri Lankan Grade 5 students. Students can buy and do the papers at a given time frame and see the marks and answers after the exam and parents can analyze children's progress according to their results. The system had several components including client frontend, API, admin panel, Android and IOS mobile apps.

Major Technologies & Tools

Angular 2, CSS, Node JS, mongo db, Android, Java, Bitbucket

Responsibilities

- Develop web application functionalities using Angular 2 to enhance the user experience and meet business objectives.
- Convert designs into HTML/CSS to ensure high-quality, responsive web pages that are visually appealing and meet user needs.
- Configure the Continuous Integration/Continuous Delivery (CI/CD) pipeline using Jenkins to automate the build and deployment process, ensuring efficient project delivery and reducing errors.

Education Qualifications

- B.Sc. in Computer Science (full-time) University of Colombo, Sri Lanka (Feb 2013 - Apr 2016)
- Advanced Business Solution Developer IJSE, Sri Lanka (Nov 2011 - Oct 2012)
- GCE Advance Level (Physical science) Dharmasoka College, Sri Lanka (May 2008 - Aug 2010)

Soft Skills

- The ability to analyze
- A collaborative approach to problem-solving
- Ability to adapt
- Work diligently
- Ability to communicate effectively
- Leadership through teamwork

Activities of Interests

- Badminton
- Traveling
- Cooking

<u>nk</u>	<u>S</u>
	<u>าห</u>

English (Reading and writing)
Sinhalese
Medium: <u>@abaywardanakasun</u>
GitHub: <u>github.com/Kasun002</u>

References

On request